Charlotte Burgis DeForest Papers, 1903-1960
Sophia Smith Collection, Smith College
Charlotte B. DeForest papers
1903-1960
DeForest, Charlotte B. (Charlotte Burgis), b. 1879.
MS 44
4 boxes (1.5 linear ft.)
Sophia Smith Collection Smith College Northampton, MA
Missionary. President, Kobe College. Papers include correspondence, memorabilia, photographs, clippings, awards and citations, and writings. Personal and professional correspondence includes letters from friends and colleagues in Japan, mostly relating to her work at Kobe College.
Charlotte Burgis DeForest was born in Osaka, Japan, in 1879. Her parents were pioneer missionaries and her father, John Hyde Deforest was decorated by Emperor Meiji for efforts to promote international friendship and for relief work during the 1906 famine. Charlotte earned an A.B. (1901) and A.M. (1907) from Smith College, and received an honorary degree from Smith in 1921. In 1903, she volunteered for service with the American Board of commissioners for Foreign Missions to work in Japan. She spent ten years on the faculty at Kobe College in Nishinomya, originally a missionary school and now the oldest Christian College in Japan. In 1915 she became President of the college, a position she retained until 1940. She was awarded the Sacred Cross by Emperor Hirohito in 1940. During World War II, DeForest returned to the United States and taught Japanese at Pomona College. She was also a counselor at the Manzanar Relocation Center, a Japanese internment camp in California, 1941-45. In 1950, DeForest was decorated by the Japanese government for "services in the education of Japanese women." After her retirement in 1950, she resided in Claremont, California. She published several books, including Evolution of a Missionary (1914), a biography of her father; Poems Down the Years; The Prancing Pony (1968), a book of Japanese nursery rhymes translated to English that won the Chicago Tribune book award; and History of Kobe College, compiled for the 75th anniversary, 1950. Charlotte DeForest died in 1973.
The Charlotte Burgis DeForest Papers consist of 1.5 linear feet and include correspondence, memorabilia, photographs, clippings, awards and citations, and writings. Personal and professional correspondence includes letters from friends and colleagues in Japan, most related to her work at Kobe College. Historical material on Kobe College includes articles by DeForest; her book, History of Kobe College; and college publications such as brochures, calendars, reports, historical sketches, and handbooks (1925-50). Writings include manuscripts of her books, the paper "Some Types of Japanese Poetry" she submitted for her Master's thesis, as well as other short pieces and poems. There is also a paper entitled "Well-known Professional Women of Japan" (1960) written by Chieko Cho. Memorabilia includes a pair of sandals, Smith College Club pins, a plaque and a book of photographs regarding the 85th anniversary of Kobe College. Clippings and articles relate to DeForest's her life and activities, and details pertinent to Kobe College. Also included is one file of Charlotte's sister, Sarah DeForest Pettus with correspondence, articles, and an essay entitled "Prison conditions in Peking" (n.d.).
This collection is organized into four series:
I. Biographical
II. Kobe College
III. Memorabilia
IV. Japanese Friends and Japanese in the US
Oversize Materials
Information on Use
Terms of Access and Use
The papers are open to research according to the regulations of the Sophia Smith Collection.
This collection has not been fully processed and therefore may be difficult to use.
History of the Collection
Charlotte Burgis DeForest donated her papers to the Sophia Smith Collection in 1960.
Search Terms
Education--Japan--History--20th century--Sources; Japan--description and travel--Sources; Kobe Jogakuin Daigaku--History--Sources; Missionaries--Japan--History--Sources; Nursery rhymes, Japanese--History--Sources; Women--Japan--History--20th century--Sources; DeForest, Charlotte B. (Charlotte Burgis), b. 1879., 1879-1973; Japanese Americans--Evacuation and relocation, 1942-1945; Japan--History--20th century--Sources
- SERIES I. BIOGRAPHICAL
  - Obituaries, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Biography, clippings, pamphlets (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Awards and citations (Box 1, Folder 3-4)
  - Correspondence
    - United States (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Letters from Japan (includes many copies), 1921-50 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Writings
    - The Prancing Pony 1967 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Some types of Japanese Poetry (Smith College Masters thesis), 1901 (Box 1, Folder 7a)
    - Transcripts (includes autobiographical sketch), 1967 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Published writings (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Some Post-War Correspondence in Japan, 1947-1950, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Patsy and I: My Conversation with the Lord in an Old Folks Home, undated (Box 1)
    - Dr. Tasuku Harada's, 115 Japanese Nursery Rhymes, 1908 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Miscellaneous short pieces (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Photographs of Charlotte DeForest (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Visas and passports (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Pettus, Sarah DeForest (sister): correspondence, articles, passport, and essay on "Prison conditions in Peking," undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
    [See also Wall hanging in Flat File (gift from women in small Chinese village)]
- SERIES II. KOBE COLLEGE
  - The History of Kobe College by Charlotte Burgis DeForest, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Calendar, charter, courses, and history (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Clippings and newsletters (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - "College Education for Women in the U.S.A.," Monkichi Namba (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Kobe College dedication, 1934 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Japan Advertiser--Kobe College Special Education (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Publications (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Reports (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Searle Chapel dedication (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Kobe College 85th Anniversary: photograph album, 1960 (Box 3)
  - "Well-Known Professional Women of Japan" by Chieko Cho 1960 (Box 3)
- SERIES III. MEMORABILIA
  - Japanese slippers (Box 4)
  - Pins (Box 4)
  - Silver plaque (Box 4)
- SERIES IV. JAPANESE FRIENDS and JAPANESE IN THE U.S.
  - Japanese in U.S.A. during war: miscellaneous, 1941-45 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Japanese in U.S.A. during war, Manzanar, CA, 1941-45 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Japanese women: articles and letter (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Cho family: correspondence to DeForest, article, and translation (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Prostitution: Japan League for the Abolition of Licensed Prostitution, 1926-29 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Hasegawa, Hatsune: articles and photos (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Otake, Matsuko: correspondence to DeForest and articles (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Cho, Chieko: translation of Japanese doctor's life of Schweitzer, 1957 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- OVERSIZE MATERIALS
  - Wall hanging from women in a small Chinese village (Map-case Flat File)